Have you seen Lady Tinasha anywhere?
What?
It seems she vanished near the end
of the coronation and has yet to return.
I haven't...
Is it Valt?
I shall order a search at once.
Just to be safe, I'll return
to Farsas for the time being.
I didn't expect you to transfer the orb
to Farsas, after the first one was stolen.
You must trust that Akashia
swordsman an awful lot.
Of course I do.
Records say that it all began
with the death of a child.
As the mother cried,
with her child's corpse in her arms,
it's said that she felt
the presence of someone else.
Use these if you want to save him.
With those words,
she received both halves of Eleterria.
The mother used them to return
to the past and saved her child.
It was an outsider who handed them to her?
Yes.
They're observing this world and its people,
after introducing these experimental artifacts.
And what of your family, the Time-Readers?
The very first child who was saved...
We are his descendants.
Every generation, one of us
is trapped as a part of Eleterria,
with our souls being used as record sheets.
Your souls?
The soul of the current family head contains
a log of all the times Eleterria is used,
as well as all of the names
of the past and future heads.
I have spent a long time
being alive, all by myself.
Time rewinds for me without mercy.
Die as I might, I find myself
back in the past, conscious yet again.
The outsider who designed this mechanism
must have given no thought to the agony
of those possessing the souls being used.
They figured that we owe
our lives to Eleterria,
and trampled all over us,
into the distant future.
That's why they must be destroyed.
Not only does destroying them
require extraordinary power,
but when one is destroyed,
the other will immediately activate.
Which is why both must be
destroyed simultaneously.
I knew that you were the only one
who seemed fit for the task,
but it was no easy feat making contact
with you when you were a witch.
I was met with frustration again and again.
However, the impossible happened.
What?
The orbs activate when they sense
a powerful attachment toward someone.
It doesn't matter whether it's love or hate.
The user's strong emotions
are what activate them.
So under normal circumstances, it should
be impossible to travel back centuries.
Who would ever be so attached
to someone from the distant past?
There was one exception, though.
A man who loved a witch and made her his wife.
Your husband.
He went back four hundred years and changed
history, so you were no longer a witch.
Hope was born in me.
Maybe this would be the time it all worked out.
It might be possible to destroy
them both at once, or so I thought.
It's not enough to simply seal Eleterria away?
The world is waiting for an upheaval.
What?
Right now, it's like a new pin is stuck
into the world every time it is altered.
Its limit is close at hand.
As proof, the furthest history will go
is thirty-one years from now at most.
The world is almost at a standstill.
Unless we destroy Eleterria,
the world will come to a stop.
No way...
At present, there is no
family head to succeed me.
How can that be?
Even if history comes to a standstill,
shouldn't there still be up to
thirty-one years left?
If you die, wouldn't the next head take over?
My soul will be dismantled
before it learns of the next family head.
Seeking magical power,
I turned to a forbidden curse,
exchanging my soul for power.
As a result, my soul was dismantled,
creating a gap in the family succession.
It seems the world saw this as
the crack it sought to tear Eleterria apart.
So no matter how much history may change,
my soul will always end up dismantled.
But eventually, I'm sure a new head
will be chosen, regardless of bloodline.
In that case, it's far better
that this all ends with me.
As long as there is one who suffers,
Eleterria can continue to be used.
As for me, I've had enough.
How foolish and selfish, to care only
about saving the people close to you.
It infuriates me.
You and your family have suffered
every time Eleterria has been used.
That's a truth we cannot overlook.
However, I can't deny the feelings
of those who used Eleterria.
That's the human heart.
To deny that would mean rejecting our humanity.
What drives Eleterria are strong emotions.
That means it can be used to save people.
Deep down, don't you agree with me?
You're not really trying to stop
the orbs from being misused.
Am I right?
That's why you're trying to
destroy them, not seal them away.
What's your reason here?
That soul that cannot be saved...
Were you really talking about yourself?
The residence you were living in...
Wasn't there a girl with you there?
Just so you understand,
I wasn't the one who cast this spell.
The caster of that spell
is who you really want to save.
I knew it.
There's one more head that succeeds him.
The final family head...
is her.
Valt?
The one whose soul will be dismantled.
The one at the center of the world stalling.
The one who will endlessly
repeat history is her.
That's why Valt shows no hesitation.
I understand your wish,
as well as the situation facing
the world and Eleterria.
That's good to hear.
Let's have you destroy them, then.
Still...
If you cannot make the choice here,
Tuldarr is sure to perish.
I know that...
Tinasha!
This way!
Of all the people...
Come with me,
or I'll have her activate the spell.
The Lake of Silence!
Stop right there.
Hand over Tinasha.
Eleterria as well.
I won't let you change history.
You're the one who overwrote it!
And we're the ones who have had
to suffer yet again because of you!
For that, I apologize.
But it all ends here.
We'll seal those orbs away,
out of everyone's reach.
No. You don't understand.
You would place your country
over all else you hold dear!
That's why I can't back down here—
Valt.
Valt. Run away.
It's fine. I can keep going.
Please, come back.
There's no point in saving me
if you disappear instead.
Instead of the happiness
I'd gain by never meeting you,
I would choose sorrow
if it means being with you.
Even if our time is limited.
Isn't that what it means to be human?
It always ends up like this
when I take my eyes off you.
I'm sorry.
It may not look like it, but I'm always
trying to find the quickest resolution.
And I'm saying that's not needed.
I can only do it because you're here for me.
They can't see the future...
That's why...
So that's why, Oscar...
I won't give up!
Please come and save me.
Even knowing Tuldarr's fate,
Oscar would not hesitate to fight.
He would be sure to stop Valt.
No lives will be lost.
I'll return to Tuldarr and break
the spell, no matter the price.
Then we can talk it over with Valt, again,
and decide what to do with Eleterria.
Washing my hands of all the burden...
Is it really right to depend on him so much?
It can't be!
What he gave me transcended
four hundred years.
I thought if I could marry him,
I would even be fine dying that very night.
But now...
Where would you like to return to?
The world will reform
at the moment of your choosing.
You'd do well to choose the safest moment
from your infinite memories of your lives.
Or perhaps the happiest.
Go on, make your choice.
My choice.
There's only one option.
By his side.
The place where he is.
The closest I can be to him.
The time when I could safely fall asleep.
Run. Go forth.
To where he is.
This time, the new records...
will be etched into your soul.
Fight.
Keep fighting.
Until you reach the ending you desire.
~ Death of the Nameless Story ~
What's wrong?
Who are you?
Who am I?
And where are we?
Still half asleep?
I'm your husband, and the king of Farsas.
You're my queen, a witch,
and the successor to Old Tuldarr.
And this is the Farsas royal bedchamber.
Should I tell you our names, too?
I'm sorry.
I really was half asleep.
Looks like it.
It's the middle of the night.
It's like I was in a dream of a different time.
It felt like I spent a really
long time getting here.
A dream of the past?
You have been alive
twenty times longer than me.
You've worked hard.
Right now, I'm really happy.
I'm glad I was able to make it to your side.
Are you okay?
In what way?
Huh?
What could it be?
It almost felt like I wasn't
able to marry you...
Huh?!
What now?!
Please wait!
Wait, we've never done this before!
You're acting weird!
The weird one here is you.
You're out of your mind.
L-Let go of me!
I refuse.
What's that?
This is...
What happened?
Oscar.
Will you listen to me?
Go ahead.
I've been on a very long journey.
What an incredible story.
I don't believe it.
I figured as much.
Tuldarr, you say...
I wish I could have seen it.
In all the countless cycles, that was the
one time that Tuldarr was able to survive.
But that history has disappeared now.
Eleterria, on the verge
of breaking, brought me back.
In the end...
I wasn't able to protect Tuldarr.
Was it a fine nation?
Yes, the finest.
So, the fact that you've retained those
memories that should have disappeared means...
I've become the head of the Time-Readers.
The way I was selected was quite unprecedented.
As an emergency measure, Eleterria
dismantled the world and reformed it.
Which means?
This world...
It was created moments ago, when I woke up.
It asked me when it should
reform the world, and I chose now.
Because among all of my memories,
this is my happiest moment.
I'm honored to hear that.
I see now.
I think I get the gist of it.
An outsiders' artifact, huh?
That said, there are other items
that work in unexplainable ways.
Huh?
I mean Akashia.
It's said that an inhuman being
pulled Akashia from the Lake of Silence.
So couldn't that being have come
from outside our world?
Now that you mention it...
I once met someone
who came from outside our world.
An outsider, but also not really.
Choosing to align herself with humans,
she lived and died among them.
How can you not know anything
about outsiders' artifacts?
That person must have been
the creator of Akashia herself.
The first queen of Farsas, Deirdre.
Deirdre    Outsider; First Queen of Farsas
The first queen?
I heard of her from Farsas royalty
four hundred years ago.
She traded her own power
to give Akashia to the founding king.
But in exchange, she couldn't
return to her homeland.
I have blood from outside
this world flowing through me?
We're talking about more than
twenty generations ago.
I imagine those traits have
completely faded away by now.
Perhaps Akashia was originally intended
to destroy outsiders' artifacts.
If the Lake of Silence
still holds the same power,
it would make sense for the lake itself
to try and destroy Eleterria.
So that's why Eleterria escaped from the lake?
Tinasha.
Yes?
Let's get going.
What?
There's another orb, right?
We need to destroy
both of them at the same time?
That's right.
Wait, you want to destroy them?!
Of course.
What?!
I understand your reasoning.
Or I guess the reasoning
of the you that argued against Valt.
I can't say how you feel now.
But if you sympathize with saving others,
even at the cost of changing the past,
if you accept having your own life
changed whenever it activates,
with your acceptance in mind,
I want to see these destroyed.
Oscar...
Destroying Eleterria and rewriting
all changes back to their original fates...
The final change, and the largest of them all.
The clan of Time-Readers will vanish,
and the fates of many alive today will change.
And Oscar, who was saved
by his mother using Eleterria...
He's sure to die then and there.
These things saved me, and I've used
them to save you, so let me say this.
Changing the past is a fruitless action.
It goes against the natural human order.
No matter your regrets,
you should live on and accept them.
There is no tragedy that can't be overcome.
I believe that all humans
have the power to do that.
This must be the reason
Akashia was passed down to me.
Don't worry.
You won't need to bear the burden by yourself.
You can always see right through me.
Oscar.
If history changes, and everything
goes back to the way it was...
Even if no memories remain,
and I end up never being born...
I will always love you.
You are the first
and last person I will ever love.
That's more than I deserve.
I love you, too.
This is nothing more than a midway point.
Don't lose your way.
Make sure you come back to me.
Our meeting...
must be the intersection of two fates
that were never meant to overlap.
That's why this is the ending we reached.
As humans.
To fight those who would interfere.
Please wait for me.
I'll make sure I find you again.
Across time.
When I do...
We can fall in love again anew.
I'll look forward to it.
Had your fun toying with humans?
Don't look down on us.
We're done being your playthings.
We reject your interference.
Return to dust and leave this world!
I've been looking for you.
Are you the one that abducted
a child from the Farsas castle city?
Damn it! A mage?
You're half right.
But that makes you wrong.
That measly spell...
That's what you get for
not being able to discern a witch.
Well, not that you'd get away if you did.
D-Don't do it!
She's dangerous, Prince Oscar!
Nice to meet you.
I'm—
Tinasha.
You're finally here.
I was sick and tired of waiting.
An old fairy tale about
a king and the fifth witch.
All stories give rise to others.
They're added on to...
and enjoyed across generations.
They can no longer be rewritten.
This is...
A fragment of an unnamed memory.